<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!-- Common Prayers -->
    <string name="prayer_sign_of_cross">In the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit. Amen.</string>
    <string name="prayer_apostles_creed">I believe in God, the Father Almighty, Creator of Heaven and earth; and in Jesus Christ, His only Son, our Lord; Who was conceived by the Holy Spirit, born of the Virgin Mary, suffered under Pontius Pilate, was crucified, died, and was buried. He descended into Hell; the third day He arose again from the dead; He ascended into Heaven, and is seated at the right hand of God, the Father Almighty; from thence He shall come to judge the living and the dead. I believe in the Holy Spirit, the Holy Catholic Church, the communion of Saints, the forgiveness of sins, the resurrection of the body, and life everlasting. Amen.</string>
    <string name="prayer_our_father">Our Father, Who art in Heaven, hallowed be Thy name; Thy Kingdom come, Thy will be done on earth as it is in Heaven. Give us this day our daily bread; and forgive us our trespasses as we forgive those who trespass against us; and lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil. Amen.</string>
    <string name="prayer_hail_mary">Hail Mary, full of grace. The Lord is with thee. Blessed art thou amongst women, and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus. Holy Mary, Mother of God, pray for us sinners, now and at the hour of our death. Amen.</string>
    <string name="prayer_hail_mary_faith">For our Faith - Hail Mary, full of grace. The Lord is with thee. Blessed art thou amongst women, and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus. Holy Mary, Mother of God, pray for us sinners, now and at the hour of our death. Amen.</string>
    <string name="prayer_hail_mary_hope">For our Hope - Hail Mary, full of grace. The Lord is with thee. Blessed art thou amongst women, and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus. Holy Mary, Mother of God, pray for us sinners, now and at the hour of our death. Amen.</string>
    <string name="prayer_hail_mary_charity">For our Charity - Hail Mary, full of grace. The Lord is with thee. Blessed art thou amongst women, and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus. Holy Mary, Mother of God, pray for us sinners, now and at the hour of our death. Amen.</string>
    <string name="prayer_glory_be">Glory be to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit. As it was in the beginning, is now, and ever shall be, world without end. Amen.</string>
    <string name="prayer_fatima">O my Jesus, forgive us our sins, save us from the fires of Hell, lead all souls to Heaven, especially those in most need of Thy mercy. Amen.</string>
    <string name="prayer_hail_holy_queen">Hail, Holy Queen, Mother of Mercy, our life, our sweetness and our hope! To thee do we cry, poor banished children of Eve; to thee do we send up our sighs, mourning and weeping in this valley of tears. Turn then, most gracious advocate, thine eyes of mercy toward us, and after this our exile, show unto us the blessed fruit of thy womb, Jesus. O clement, O loving, O sweet Virgin Mary! Pray for us, O Holy Mother of God, that we may be made worthy of the promises of Christ.</string>
    <string name="prayer_rosary">Let us pray. O God, whose only begotten Son, by His life, death, and resurrection, has purchased for us the rewards of eternal life, grant, we beseech Thee, that meditating upon these mysteries of the Most Holy Rosary of the Blessed Virgin Mary, we may imitate what they contain and obtain what they promise, through the same Christ Our Lord. Amen.</string>

    <!-- Prayer Titles -->
    <string name="title_sign_of_cross">Sign of the Cross</string>
    <string name="title_apostles_creed">Apostles\&apos; Creed</string>
    <string name="title_our_father">Our Father</string>
    <string name="title_hail_mary">Hail Mary</string>
    <string name="title_hail_mary_faith">Hail Mary (1/3)</string>
    <string name="title_hail_mary_hope">Hail Mary (2/3)</string>
    <string name="title_hail_mary_charity">Hail Mary (3/3)</string>
    <string name="title_hail_mary_decade">Hail Mary (%d/10)</string>
    <string name="title_glory_be">Glory Be</string>
    <string name="title_fatima_prayer">Fatima Prayer</string>
    <string name="title_hail_holy_queen">Hail Holy Queen</string>
    <string name="title_rosary_prayer">Rosary Prayer</string>
    
    <!-- Joyful Mysteries -->
    <string-array name="joyful_mysteries_titles">
        <item>The Annunciation</item>
        <item>The Visitation</item>
        <item>The Nativity</item>
        <item>The Presentation in the Temple</item>
        <item>The Finding in the Temple</item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string-array name="joyful_mysteries_descriptions">
        <item>Reading: Luke 1:26-38 (ESV)\n\nIn the sixth month the angel Gabriel was sent from God to a city of Galilee named Nazareth, to a virgin betrothed to a man whose name was Joseph, of the house of David. And the virgin\'s name was Mary. And he came to her and said, \"Greetings, favored one, the Lord is with you!\" But she was greatly troubled at the saying, and tried to discern what sort of greeting this might be. And the angel said to her, \"Do not be afraid, Mary, for you have found favor with God. And behold, you will conceive in your womb and bear a son, and you shall call his name Jesus. He will be great and will be called the Son of the Most High. And the Lord God will give to him the throne of his father David, and he will reign over the house of Jacob forever, and of his kingdom there will be no end.\" And Mary said to the angel, \"How will this be, since I am a virgin?\" And the angel answered her, \"The Holy Spirit will come upon you, and the power of the Most High will overshadow you; therefore the child to be born will be called holy—the Son of God. And behold, your relative Elizabeth in her old age has also conceived a son, and this is the sixth month with her who was called barren. For nothing will be impossible with God.\" And Mary said, \"Behold, I am the servant of the Lord; let it be to me according to your word.\" And the angel departed from her.</item>
        <item>Reading: Luke 1:39-45 (ESV)\n\nIn those days Mary arose and went with haste into the hill country, to a town in Judah, and she entered the house of Zechariah and greeted Elizabeth. And when Elizabeth heard the greeting of Mary, the baby leaped in her womb. And Elizabeth was filled with the Holy Spirit, and she exclaimed with a loud cry, \"Blessed are you among women, and blessed is the fruit of your womb! And why is this granted to me that the mother of my Lord should come to me? For behold, when the sound of your greeting came to my ears, the baby in my womb leaped for joy. And blessed is she who believed that there would be a fulfillment of what was spoken to her from the Lord.\"</item>
        <item>Reading: Luke 2:1-7 (ESV)\n\nIn those days a decree went out from Caesar Augustus that all the world should be registered. This was the first registration when Quirinius was governor of Syria. And all went to be registered, each to his own town. And Joseph also went up from Galilee, from the town of Nazareth, to Judea, to the city of David, which is called Bethlehem, because he was of the house and lineage of David, to be registered with Mary, his betrothed, who was with child. And while they were there, the time came for her to give birth. And she gave birth to her firstborn son and wrapped him in swaddling cloths and laid him in a manger, because there was no place for them in the inn.</item>
        <item>Reading: Luke 2:22-38 (ESV)\n\nAnd when the time came for their purification according to the Law of Moses, they brought him up to Jerusalem to present him to the Lord (as it is written in the Law of the Lord, \"Every male who first opens the womb shall be called holy to the Lord\") and to offer a sacrifice according to what is said in the Law of the Lord, \"a pair of turtledoves, or two young pigeons.\" Now there was a man in Jerusalem, whose name was Simeon, and this man was righteous and devout, waiting for the consolation of Israel, and the Holy Spirit was upon him. And it had been revealed to him by the Holy Spirit that he would not see death before he had seen the Lord\'s Christ. And he came in the Spirit into the temple, and when the parents brought in the child Jesus, to do for him according to the custom of the Law, he took him up in his arms and blessed God and said, \"Lord, now you are letting your servant depart in peace, according to your word; for my eyes have seen your salvation that you have prepared in the presence of all peoples, a light for revelation to the Gentiles, and for glory to your people Israel.\" And his father and his mother marveled at what was said about him. And Simeon blessed them and said to Mary his mother, \"Behold, this child is appointed for the fall and rising of many in Israel, and for a sign that is opposed (and a sword will pierce through your own soul also), so that thoughts from many hearts may be revealed.\" And there was a prophetess, Anna, the daughter of Phanuel, of the tribe of Asher. She was advanced in years, having lived with her husband seven years from when she was a virgin, and then as a widow until she was eighty-four. She did not depart from the temple, worshiping with fasting and prayer night and day. And coming up at that very hour she began to give thanks to God and to speak of him to all who were waiting for the redemption of Jerusalem.</item>
        <item>Reading: Luke 2:41-52 (ESV)\n\nNow his parents went to Jerusalem every year at the Feast of the Passover. And when he was twelve years old, they went up according to custom. And when the feast was ended, as they were returning, the boy Jesus stayed behind in Jerusalem. His parents did not know it, but supposing him to be in the group they went a day\'s journey, but then they began to search for him among their relatives and acquaintances, and when they did not find him, they returned to Jerusalem, searching for him. After three days they found him in the temple, sitting among the teachers, listening to them and asking them questions. And all who heard him were amazed at his understanding and his answers. And when his parents saw him, they were astonished. And his mother said to him, \"Son, why have you treated us so? Behold, your father and I have been searching for you in great distress.\" And he said to them, \"Why were you looking for me? Did you not know that I must be in my Father\'s house?\" And they did not understand the saying that he spoke to them. And he went down with them and came to Nazareth and was submissive to them. And his mother treasured up all these things in her heart. And Jesus increased in wisdom and in stature and in favor with God and man.</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Luminous Mysteries -->
    <string-array name="luminous_mysteries_titles">
        <item>The Baptism in the Jordan</item>
        <item>The Wedding at Cana</item>
        <item>The Proclamation of the Kingdom</item>
        <item>The Transfiguration</item>
        <item>The Institution of the Eucharist</item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string-array name="luminous_mysteries_descriptions">
        <item>Reading: Matthew 3:13-17 (ESV)\n\nThen Jesus came from Galilee to the Jordan to John, to be baptized by him. John would have prevented him, saying, \"I need to be baptized by you, and do you come to me?\" But Jesus answered him, \"Let it be so now, for thus it is fitting for us to fulfill all righteousness.\" Then he consented. And when Jesus was baptized, immediately he went up from the water, and behold, the heavens were opened to him, and he saw the Spirit of God descending like a dove and coming to rest on him; and behold, a voice from heaven said, \"This is my beloved Son, with whom I am well pleased.\"</item>
        <item>Reading: John 2:1-11 (ESV)\n\nOn the third day there was a wedding at Cana in Galilee, and the mother of Jesus was there. Jesus also was invited to the wedding with his disciples. When the wine ran out, the mother of Jesus said to him, \"They have no wine.\" And Jesus said to her, \"Woman, what does this have to do with me? My hour has not yet come.\" His mother said to the servants, \"Do whatever he tells you.\" Now there were six stone water jars there for the Jewish rites of purification, each holding twenty or thirty gallons. Jesus said to the servants, \"Fill the jars with water.\" And they filled them up to the brim. And he said to them, \"Now draw some out and take it to the master of the feast.\" So they took it. When the master of the feast tasted the water now become wine, and did not know where it came from (though the servants who had drawn the water knew), the master of the feast called the bridegroom and said to him, \"Everyone serves the good wine first, and when people have drunk freely, then the poor wine. But you have kept the good wine until now.\" This, the first of his signs, Jesus did at Cana in Galilee, and manifested his glory. And his disciples believed in him.</item>
        <item>Reading: Mark 1:14-15 (ESV)\n\nNow after John was arrested, Jesus came into Galilee, proclaiming the gospel of God, and saying, \"The time is fulfilled, and the kingdom of God is at hand; repent and believe in the gospel.\"</item>
        <item>Reading: Matthew 17:1-8 (ESV)\n\nAnd after six days Jesus took with him Peter and James, and John his brother, and led them up a high mountain by themselves. And he was transfigured before them, and his face shone like the sun, and his clothes became white as light. And behold, there appeared to them Moses and Elijah, talking with him. And Peter said to Jesus, \"Lord, it is good that we are here. If you wish, I will make three tents here, one for you and one for Moses and one for Elijah.\" He was still speaking when, behold, a bright cloud overshadowed them, and a voice from the cloud said, \"This is my beloved Son, with whom I am well pleased; listen to him.\" When the disciples heard this, they fell on their faces and were terrified. But Jesus came and touched them, saying, \"Rise, and have no fear.\" And when they lifted up their eyes, they saw no one but Jesus only.</item>
        <item>Reading: Matthew 26:26-28 (ESV)\n\nNow as they were eating, Jesus took bread, and after blessing it broke it and gave it to the disciples, and said, \"Take, eat; this is my body.\" And he took a cup, and when he had given thanks he gave it to them, saying, \"Drink of it, all of you, for this is my blood of the covenant, which is poured out for many for the forgiveness of sins.\"</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Sorrowful Mysteries -->
    <string-array name="sorrowful_mysteries_titles">
        <item>The Agony in the Garden</item>
        <item>The Scourging at the Pillar</item>
        <item>The Crowning with Thorns</item>
        <item>The Carrying of the Cross</item>
        <item>The Crucifixion and Death</item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string-array name="sorrowful_mysteries_descriptions">
        <item>Reading: Matthew 26:36-46 (ESV)\n\nThen Jesus went with them to a place called Gethsemane, and he said to his disciples, \"Sit here, while I go over there and pray.\" And taking with him Peter and the two sons of Zebedee, he began to be sorrowful and troubled. Then he said to them, \"My soul is very sorrowful, even to death; remain here, and watch with me.\" And going a little farther he fell on his face and prayed, saying, \"My Father, if it be possible, let this cup pass from me; nevertheless, not as I will, but as you will.\" And he came to the disciples and found them sleeping. And he said to Peter, \"So, could you not watch with me one hour? Watch and pray that you may not enter into temptation. The spirit indeed is willing, but the flesh is weak.\" Again for the second time he went away and prayed, \"My Father, if this cannot pass unless I drink it, your will be done.\" And again he came and found them sleeping, for their eyes were heavy. So leaving them again, he went away and prayed for the third time, saying the same words again. Then he came to the disciples and said to them, \"Sleep and take your rest later on. See, the hour is at hand, and the Son of Man is betrayed into the hands of sinners. Rise, let us be going; see, my betrayer is at hand.\"</item>
        <item>Reading: John 19:1 (ESV)\n\nThen Pilate took Jesus and flogged him.</item>
        <item>Reading: John 19:2-3 (ESV)\n\nAnd the soldiers twisted together a crown of thorns and put it on his head and arrayed him in a purple robe. They came up to him, saying, \"Hail, King of the Jews!\" and struck him with their hands.</item>
        <item>Reading: Luke 23:26-32 (ESV)\n\nAnd as they led him away, they seized one Simon of Cyrene, who was coming in from the country, and laid on him the cross, to carry it behind Jesus. And there followed him a great multitude of the people and of women who were mourning and lamenting for him. But turning to them Jesus said, \"Daughters of Jerusalem, do not weep for me, but weep for yourselves and for your children. For behold, the days are coming when they will say, \'Blessed are the barren and the wombs that never bore and the breasts that never nursed!\' Then they will begin to say to the mountains,\'Fall on us,\' and to the hills, \'Cover us.\' For if they do these things when the wood is green, what will happen when it is dry?\"</item>
        <item>Reading: John 19:28-30 (ESV)\n\nAfter this, Jesus, knowing that all was now finished, said (to fulfill the Scripture), \"I thirst.\" A jar full of sour wine stood there. So they put a sponge full of the sour wine on a hyssop branch and held it to his mouth. When Jesus had received the sour wine, he said, \"It is finished,\" and he bowed his head and gave up his spirit.</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Glorious Mysteries -->
    <string-array name="glorious_mysteries_titles">
        <item>The Resurrection</item>
        <item>The Ascension</item>
        <item>The Descent of the Holy Spirit</item>
        <item>The Assumption</item>
        <item>The Coronation of the Virgin</item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string-array name="glorious_mysteries_descriptions">
        <item>Reading: John 20:1-10 (ESV)\n\nNow on the first day of the week Mary Magdalene came to the tomb early, while it was still dark, and saw that the stone had been taken away from the tomb. So she ran and went to Simon Peter and the other disciple, the one whom Jesus loved, and said to them, \"They have taken the Lord out of the tomb, and we do not know where they have laid him.\" So Peter went out with the other disciple, and they were going toward the tomb. Both of them were running together, but the other disciple outran Peter and reached the tomb first. And stooping to look in, he saw the linen cloths lying there, but he did not go in. Then Simon Peter came, following him, and went into the tomb. He saw the linen cloths lying there, and the face cloth, which had been on Jesus\' head, not lying with the linen cloths but folded up in a place by itself. Then the other disciple, who had reached the tomb first, also went in, and he saw and believed; for as yet they did not understand the Scripture, that he must rise from the dead. Then the disciples went back to their homes.</item>
        <item>Reading: Matthew 28:16-20 (ESV)\n\nNow the eleven disciples went to Galilee, to the mountain to which Jesus had directed them. And when they saw him they worshiped him, but some doubted. And Jesus came and said to them, \"All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. Go therefore and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, teaching them to observe all that I have commanded you. And behold, I am with you always, to the end of the age.\"</item>
        <item>Reading: Acts 2:1-4 (ESV)\n\nWhen the day of Pentecost arrived, they were all together in one place. And suddenly there came from heaven a sound like a mighty rushing wind, and it filled the entire house where they were sitting. And divided tongues as of fire appeared to them and rested on each one of them. And they were all filled with the Holy Spirit and began to speak in other tongues as the Spirit gave them utterance.</item>
        <item>Reading: Luke 1:46-49 (ESV)\n\nAnd Mary said, \"My soul magnifies the Lord, and my spirit rejoices in God my Savior, for he has looked on the humble estate of his servant. For behold, from now on all generations will call me blessed; for he who is mighty has done great things for me, and holy is his name.\"</item>
        <item>Reading: Revelation 12:1 (ESV)\n\nAnd a great sign appeared in heaven: a woman clothed with the sun, with the moon under her feet, and on her head a crown of twelve stars.</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>